Marcus Loo Vergara

Trondheim, Norway

☎ NO +47 411 78 583 • @ marcus.loo.vergara@gmail.com • ♦ bitsauce.github.io

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Senior student at the Norwegian University of Science and Technology working towards a master's degree in Computer Science. Specializing in computer graphics and computer vision, with a recent focus on deep learning. Expecting graduation June 2019. Self-motivated, quick learner, and enjoy helping others.

• C/C++

Python

TCP & UDP

OptiX & CUDA

• Deep Learning

• React Native

OpenGL & GLSL

• Keras, PyTorch & TensorFlow

JavaScript, HTML & CSS

EDUCATION

University of California, San Diego, San Diego, USA

Oct 2017 - Jun 2018

Master of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.49

Studied at UC San Diego for a year

Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Trondheim, Norway Master of Science in Computer Science

Aug 2013 – Expected Jun 2019

GPA: 3.00

• Specializing in computer graphics, computer vision, and deep learning

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Graphics Software Engineering Intern, Sony PlayStation

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

Internship at PlayStation's Developer Technology Group (DTG)

- Created a performance analysis tool to help DTG more quickly debug and suggest improvements to our customers regarding their GPU performance on the PlayStation 4TM
- Implemented physically-based shading on the PlayStation 4TM
- Exposure to low-level programming for specialized hardware
- Gained experience in teamwork and good coding practices
- Trained an autoencoder to generate metallic, roughness and ambient occlusion textures

Software Developer, Grabster

Jul 2017 – Aug 2017

Summer job assisting a start-up in app development

- Grabster is a sharing economy platform based on buying and selling food between individuals
- Implemented and tested screen navigation and backend functionality for the Android app
- Gained experience in using React Native and Node.js

Teaching Assistant, Norwegian University of Science and Technology

Aug 2015 - May 2017

On-campus part-time job assisting students

- Support and advising in solving theoretical and practical questions
- Graded assignments
- Assigned subjects:
 - Aug 2015 Dec 2015: Computers and Digital Design (Assembly programming)
 - Jan 2016 May 2017: Procedural and object-oriented programming (C++)

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Human Keypoint Detection, CSE 252C Course Project

Jun 2018

Created a Mask R-CNN based model to detect human keypoints in images of people

- Uses Mask R-CNN for instance-level bounding box and keypoint detections
- Trained with Keras and TensorFlow

Deep Learning on Point Cloud Data, CSE 291-100 Course Project

Apr 2018

Used the convolutional architectures PointNet and PointNet++ to segment stem and leaf points in 3D point scans of plants in various stages of growth and various environments

• Experimented with different data preprocessing to enable PointNet for big (1+ million) point clouds

OptiX Project, CSE 274 Course project

Mar 2018

Used NVIDIA's OptiX ray tracer to implement Axis-Aligned Filtering for Interactive Sampled Soft Shadows

• Provided a fundamental understanding of the use of frequency analysis in ray tracing

Image Captioning, CSE 190-C00 Course Project

Dec 2017

Used LSTMs to generate captions for input images

• CNN extracts features from image and recurrent LSTMs generate image captions

Recommender Systems, CSE 258 Course project

Nov 2017

Used bag-of-word techniques to identify user preferences by their comment history

- Used linear regression, SVMs and latent factor models to make predictions on user preferences
- Participated in a Kaggle competition for the class reached top 90%
- Used Reddit API to mine comments and post history through PRAW

Autonomous Vehicle Perception, TDT4265 Course Project

May 2017

Trained a model based on Faster R-CNN recognize and locate cars in images

• Setting up a development environment in Ubuntu to train the deep network in Caffe

Game Engine Programming, Side-project

2010 - Present

Writing a game engine from scratch in C++ with OpenGL

- Ongoing side-project of 7 years
- Used the game engine to make a procedurally generated 2D game

CAMPUS ACTIVITIES

Abakus GameDev, Norwegian University of Science and Technology

Aug 2014 – Present Co-founder and leader of student organization *Abakus GameDev*: a student organization for people who enjoy making games and discussing various topics in game design

- Responsible for creating frameworks for AI competitions
- · Participating in meetings, discussing workshop ideas, and advertising